PATRICIO CORDEIRO

I am a software developer enthusiast, teacher, writer and learner. I enjoy learning new technologies and sharing knowledge with others. I have over 10 years in software development and my main experiences are with Frontend development using Angular, Flutter, Ionic, ReactJs and React Native. I also have experience in Backend development using NodeJs (including NestJs), Microservices with Docker and Kubemetes. Some of my other experiences are: app publishing, Firebase and AWS.

Rua Artur Thiré Bosque da Saúde, 343, Vila da Saúde, CEP: 04146-000, São Paulo - SP

(11) 98306-3175

paponcio6@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/patricio-cordeiro-04040839

GOALS

At the moment I'm focused on:

Angular

Flutter

Ionic

React is

React Native

NodeJs



EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARA

2009 – 2011 Electrical and Computer Engineering

DEGREE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARA

2003 – 2008 Electrical and Computer Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ZUP IT INNOVATION

2020 - CURRENT

TECH LEAD

I work on a renovation project for one of Itaú bank's most important applications. Working daily with management, design system, business, architecture team, etc. Acts in the definition of Frontend Mobile, UX and governance architecture solutions. I use React Native and Flutter frameworks in the implementation of mini-apps, as proofs of concept for a new architecture.

We are currently working on a large platform deployment project at Banco Itaú(using Angular 9 and 12). I am responsible for leading and managing the development team, designing architectural solutions, ensuring code quality, reviewing code, applying good development practices, plan the flow of development and delivery of functionalities. Intermediary of the business team with the development team to guarantee the technical execution of the needs and priorities of the business.

i am also responsible for the implementation of pipelines on AWS and management of publications in deployment environments and also development of reusable libraries, microfrontends and creation and management of technical documentation.

BRQ DIGITAL SOLUTIONS (ANDBANK-BRASIL)

TECH LEAD

Worked on a large project to implement a WEB platform (using Angular+) for financial investments. Responsible for managing the development team, designing architectural solutions, ensuring code quality and good development practices. Intermediary of the business team with the development team to ensure technical execution of business needs and priorities.

CCEE

2018 - 2019

APPOLICE DESENVOLVIMENTOS

2017 - 2018

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARA

2015 - 2017

LABORATÓRIO DE SENSORES E SISTEMAS EMBARCADOS

2009 - 2017

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Working on two projects (with more than 30 people) as a Senior Frontend developer using Angular+. Development using SCRUM methodology. Implementation of pages with high complexity. Implementation of API consumption services, design and componentization of modules.

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Responsible for planning, gathering prerequisites and specifications of all projects of Frontend websites, mobile applications and Backend. Project development with Angularjs, Ionic, NodeJs and MongoDB. Maintenance of servers (Heroku), databases and publication of the applications in the Apple Store and Google Play Store

PROFESSOR OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Taught courses in Digital Electronics, Laboratory of Digital Electronics, Microcontrollers and Microprocessors and Laboratory of Microcontrollers.

RESEARCHER AND PROJECT MANAGER

Contributed to and managed several software and hardware projects, where he applied his web development experiences in user interface projects to control hardware prototypes. In the projects, he mainly applied AngularJs and the C language. Managed interdisciplinary work teams through the application of the SCRUM methodology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ANGULARJS 1	••••	REACT NATIVE	••••	RXJS	••••
ANGULAR+	••••	REACT	••••	NGRX	••••
IONIC	••••	MYSQL	••••	MOBX	••••
FLUTTER	••••	GIT	••••	KUBERNETES	••••
NODEJS	••••	JENKINS	••••	DOCKER	••••
MONGODB	••••	FIREBASE	••••	POSTGRESQL	••••
JAVA	••••	ANDROID	••••	AWS S3, CLOUDFRONT, SNS.	••••



LANGUAGES